then he was going to do another warm-up
set before his team was just like no no
no no no just go for the pr just hit it
dude you can do it and he just does it
but we now have a verified equipped
900lb squat from a high schooler kind of
got to see it to believe it do we have
to cover everything through the lens of
but North Korea isn't there and who
knows what it would have been if they
were are we at that point that's a great
question Phil I
think welcome to strength weekly the
weekly internet video show is TV even
still alive I don't know that brings you
everything you need to know from around
the barbell game I Am David Thomas toow
joined by Phil I'm so wide I walk
sideways through doors due to all the
lat pull Downs Blackman and we are
bringing you the four biggest stories
from around the barbell game this week
Phil any of these excite you just yes or
no please blink twice if you're being
held
hostage
yes I BL like six times I BL like six
times you BL like six times okay you
know what it's fine it's fine we a
little recording delay recording delay
it's fine we are not being held against
our will but we are excited to bring you
some big lifts this week let's get to
the taale of the tape the rundown our
run of
show John hack one of the top ranked
powerlifters in the world by just about
every metric pulls a deadlift PR of 420
kg in training we talk about his journey
toward doing the one thought impossible
2400 lb powerlifting total is a nons
super heavyweight in other news a high
school senior squats 900 lb equipped
exqueeze me the Rogue Invitational the
first time that competition is taking
place outside of the United States will
feature strong women for the first time
we talk about that competition later
this year what it means and the insane
and complex Prize Package and finally a
mysterious weightlifter from North Korea
sets three world records at the last
qualifying event before the Paris
Olympics but will not be competing in
Paris Phil of these four stor
which are you thinking will capture our
readers hearts and Minds the most I'm a
sucker that strong woman is getting the
nod at the Rogue Invitational for the
first time in Aberdine Scotland that's
where my head's at more than just the
nod they're getting the bag we're going
to talk about prize payouts and I'm
actually especially excited about that
because guess what spoiler alert the
strong women and strong men same Prize
Package from Rogue big big big deal here
all right Phil John hack Phil you've
been writing about strength sports for
what five years fiveish years yeah about
five yeah wow yeah and for how many of
those years has John hack been just
about the best powerlifter in the world
all of them every single one of them
like every time this dude is pushing the
numbers Beyond where we're like that's
not possible and then he does it and
then you know you watch his training
videos and everything is like everything
he does is super casual and you're like
yeah there's no way he's going to do it
and he just like yep he's like I know
these numbers this is the number for
this this is the number for that I'll
try and hit that he's calling his shot
for 24 00 powerlifting total at the wrpf
G ghost Clash 3 that's like a notorious
event at this point for like people
going to crush records if they have any
Targets and it would be a shocker if he
doesn't score the total that he's going
for even though it seems obscene all
right Phil first off I'm just GNA give a
quick shout out to John hack for keeping
strength Sports journalists writers and
video pundits like us in a job thank you
John for single-handedly putting the
entire industry and our careers on your
back in so many ways yeah so he locked
out 420 kilogram PR in training less
than a month before the ghost Clash 3
now we got to see what his warmup up to
that point looks like a cool behind the-
scenes look at what it's like to achieve
like the best powerlifter in the game in
his weight class just hitting his PR and
training and seeing the build up to that
so very cool if you're an Insider that
loves like seeing how powerlifters at
the top of their sport at the top of the
game actually get there so he did some
warm-up sets of 75 Kg 175 kg 275 kg 300
25 kilograms we're getting into where
people's numbers are at the top tier he
had 375 kilograms then he was going to
do another warm-up set before his team
was just like no no no no no just go for
the pr just hit it dude you can do it
and he just does it and like for anybody
who is like ever trained with training
Partners where they're just like yeah
you're actually slowing yourself down
just go for the big number I mean if
you're the best powerlifter in the world
and then you have training partners that
are like dude you can just do it why are
you getting in your own way I I found
that uh resonant for me as uh somebody
who often gets in his own way to see
that even the top tier lifters even
though they're doing it with ridiculous
weights like this is not a fathomable
lift by any metric for somebody who's
not John hack but to see that at the top
tier two kind of inspiring almost in a
weird way it was kind of cool I can just
imagine like the the the old shy buff
GIF that Meme from years ago do it do it
it just having that in front of you
right in your line of vision I'm just i'
just be that training partner it in fact
I'd be such an annoying training partner
uh I I would say hey I'm not going to
stop being annoying until you PR that
might be the the optimal motivation uh
that is that is needed absolutely what
is hack going to have to do and what is
he planning on doing specifically by a
breakdown of lifts to hit the
2,400 pound total which by the way in
his weight category would be history
making yes it it would it unprecedented
up into this point and fortunately For
Us Hack who has been putting all of
these uh strength Sports journalists on
his back for years as you said actually
did give us the breakdown of the targets
that he expects to hit at the ghost
Clash so for the squat his Target is 365
a half kilos for the bench press 268
kilos of course Johan hack the best
bench presser in the world probably for
the deadlift he's going to hit 410 now
that's after he's hit both a squat and a
deadlift we have seen him be able to
lock out 10 kilograms more than that in
training so obviously once he makes
weight he's expecting to be able to hit
410 that would be remarkable and that
would total him to 1,4 43 half kilos or
2400 lb there's just not much more to
say it might happen very good chance
it'll happen looking forward to it and
we'll cover it here on strength weekly
like sometimes I have like cheeky little
things to say at the end of segments I I
don't when it comes to John hack just
John like got speed do your think prise
beise be well we we've talked about we
have talked about the current one of the
current best power power lifters in the
world who's worn that crown for a number
of years let's talk about an up and
cominging powerlifter uh still when I
was in high school mhm at the high
school waight room in the high school
weight room uh people would um uh you
know maybe use a little bit of hyperbole
when it came to Big lifts they would say
oh my cousin at a different school just
squatted this much did this much you
know oh he totally did this much now
these weren't necessarily the
competition standard and a lot of these
numbers were uh inflated a little bit
you know someone's cousin squatted 450
lbs that's pretty cool for them you know
what I mean getting recruited go D1
maybe but we now have a verified
equipped 900 lb squat from a high
schooler kind of got to see it to
believe it uh Phil what's going on here
yeah so Dwayne Coleman of Slidell
Louisiana he's a uh high school student
this article about him squatting 900 lb
48 kilos went viral everyone covered it
just the idea that a high school student
was able to like lock this weight out
equipped of course like okay sure
whatever 900 lb on this kid's back dude
he's in when I was in high school I I
didn't know who I was I'm still trying
to find my way in the world this dude's
just like yep put 900 pounds on the back
let's squat it so he let's give a quick
rundown of his day he bench pressed 500
lb and then he deadlifted 630 PBS after
he squat 900 lb Louisiana State records
all of this good stuff for uh reference
he weighed 462 pounds so he's super
heavy weight as a high school student
29.5 kilos of body weight lifting 48
kilos of body weight just how how often
are we going to see this kind of athlete
come around at that age and pull off
something like this on camera cool thing
about it is anybody gets the luxury to
watch this video that was filmed his 900
pound squat was a fourth lift it was an
additional lift outside of the
competition that is often done that we
see at Elite competitions as well for
people who want to take shots at World
Records yeah it's really just it's not
something that would count necessarily
towards your total on the day because
that wouldn't be fair but it's like if
but you could still so sometimes people
will squat it or deadlift it or bench
press it and it won't cter their total
but it'll get them a record right it's
just depending on the Federation
depending on the competition I actually
like that about powerlifting I think
it's kind of cool you don't see that in
weightlifting you don't really see a
fourth clean in jerk attempt you know
what I mean um when it comes a super
heavyweight power lifters to watch for
the next Generation add add one to the
Whiteboard put Dwayne Coleman on the
list I mean that that was one of the uh
things that was still up in the air is
like is he going to continue as a
competitive powerlifter after he gets
after he leaves High School one caveat
to note here the previous so his squat
of course breaks the Louisiana High
School records who knows what those are
but we do know that he cracked it by 185
pounds that's how much he exceeded the
record by like when we talking like you
know top uh like Elite powerlifters
going for World Records they may chip a
world record sometimes you see the best
of the best they can tack on like 10
pounds as the upper echelon of like and
and that's something that would make
strength weekly that's like a thing that
we report on that that's like
unbelievable that would be like the Talk
of the Town for all of the world of
powerlifting if that if something like
that happens like we've seen something
like agao has just been crushing
recently has like been sort of in that
space like hitting six pounds over or
whatever and we're just like
mind-boggled by that he Dwayne Coleman
crushed it by 185 lb I hope he stays in
the game because man he would be fun to
cover well let's move on and talk about
another strength sport it's enough
powerlifting for the day no more
powerlifting today cuz we're going to
talk about strong man and strong woman
specifically strong woman now the 2024
Rogue Invitational happening later this
year is taking place outside of the
United States for the first ever time
taking place in
Scotland exciting stuff I actually
applaud that move it's an international
sport take a big competition
International I I I'm I'm a fan of that
look the Rogue Invitational CrossFit has
been a big part of that strongman in
recent years has become a big part of
that it's become one of the biggest
strongman competitions of the year
they're adding strong woman this year
and what I love is that the Prize
Package that's been announced for the
strong woman competitors is the
same as has been announced for the
strong man competitors
Phil you cover strong man strong woman
maybe more than just about anyone else
in the world what what are the
implications for the sport based on this
announcement this is probably the
biggest uh level up for strong women
that I can recall in recent memory
because the Rogue Invitational has been
the highest prize purse for strong men
for the past couple of years more than
World's Strongest Man more than Arnold
Classic like it has been Rog ational as
the top prize purse now even if it may
not have the same historic Prestige as
something like the World's Strongest Man
you get the top talent bringing their
aame because the purse is the highest at
the Rogue so in the past couple of years
we've seen Alexi Alexi novakov win it
we've seen Martin Le's win it we've seen
Mitchell Hooper win it I mean these are
all former world Strongest Man
competitors everybody's bringing their
aame Tom stman was a runner up to Le's
he's always at on the podium as well
he's a two-time world strongest man like
you see the best of the best bring their
best because the prize purse
incentivizes them to do so and to see
the strong women getting added and not
only added but added at an equivalent
prize purse as the men which have been
in Road competition for the past couple
of years now this is a significant level
up for strong women competition by
scales of magnitude the largest prize
purse for strong women ever that we know
of ever that we know of yeah this is a
six six figure plus prize purse at the
time that we're talking about this it's
already at
$117,000 like that will increas because
of the complexities of how they manage
the prize Burse it includes like a
percentage of ticket sales and a
percentage of merch sales and like but
the the initial investment that Rogue
puts in of a million dollars there's a
bunch of different factors that go into
calculating what the price pool is but
the strong men and the strong women will
get the same percentage and the same
percentage broken down across down the
leaderboard from first all the way to
10th it's an Invitational Tournament so
it'll be 10 athletes on both for the
strong women and the strong men unless
they announce some changes in addition
to that but you'll have 10 strong women
competing for the largest prize per
first place will get six figures as far
as we know it's the first time a six
figure prize press has ever happened for
strong women that is a huge deal it is
setting the standard for the sport going
forward and I just want to read that the
prize pull for the Rogue Invitational
now all athlete prizes come out of this
right so when I talk about the prize
pool what I'm about to describe
strongman prizes strong woman prizes
CrossFit prizes right there's a prize
pool so this is not to say like I'm
going to read that you know uh a number
per ticket sold right that's not
necessarily just going to the strong
woman competitors that's going to the
prize poll from which all of the prizes
come but basically we say that right now
as of this
reporting whoever wins the 2024 Rogue
strong woman Invitational will get about
$117,000 a little over that is likely to
increase because the rose Rogue prize
poll gets added to based on the
following metrics all right it's a
million doll cash investment from
rogue2 $75,000 of Bitcoin at $335,000 of
coin bit higher than that right now
which is subject to change in value as
the competition nears $5 per attendee
ticket sold 10% of online registration
fees 10% of registration fees for the
community event $5 for every Rogue
Invitational t-shirt sold $5 for every
pair of G Ruck ballistic trainers sold
through roguefitness.com Rogue is very
transparent about where the money for
the prize pool is coming from I like
that it's cool that we get to see it
increase and like if you buy a t-shirt
right you know that $5 of that is going
toward this prize pool and eventually
making its way to the athletes pockets
it's kind of neat you register for the
online qualifier you register for the
community event you know part of your
fee is going toward these athletes and
you know exactly how much of it is going
toward these athletes which is really
neat I gotta be honest I sort of wish
more competitions did that they told you
hey if you bought merch here's exactly
how much is going to the athletes right
I would kind of I would I would welcome
that transparency for most competition
that's just me to add on to that we are
recording this it is April the first
week of April that this is that you're
seeing this this contest is not until
November so all of these registration
fees however much merch is sold like it
is fully expected that the prize pool
will increase even further than this the
fact that it's already over six figures
for the top strong women athlete at this
time is remarkable so like it will only
get bigger this is this is the Paradigm
now all right let's move on to another
important milestone in women's strength
Sports and that's that the iwf World Cup
the 2024 iwf World Cup is the last
qualifying event before the Paris
Olympics so big qualification
implications for a lot of top athletes
in the sport of weightlifting and
remember weightlifting in the Paris
Olympics has fewer spots than we have
seen in decades when it comes to
athletes competing right there aren't
that many slots available countries
cannot send you know eight men and eight
women to the Olympic this year it ain't
happening because there aren't that many
Olympic spots there aren't that many
Olympic body weight categories I just
want to give that as context one team
that will not be at the Paris Olympics
is North Korea we'll get to that in a
second something important happened in
the lightest body weight session of the
iwf World Cup weight ler Juan H Sim of
North Korea set three world records in
the 45 kilo weight category it's also
not an Olympic weight category just to
be clear starts at 49 kilos three three
world records and she continues her run
as the only athlete in that bodyweight
category to ever set senior World
Records
Phil how'd she do on the day so let's
break it down for the snatch she hit 87
kilograms world record for the cleaning
jerk 109 kilograms that's a world record
you put two world records together
obviously you're getting a total of
world record of 196 kg she's the only
lifter to set World Records because they
have to to exceed the world standard
right now when the body weight
categories were introduced going on six
years ago the new ones World standards
were set and it was basically hey you
have to eclipse this in order to set a
world record right so someone couldn't
just take the first lift in an
international competition uh and like
claim a world record right after those
body weight categories were introduced
it was a way to just like make World
Records like mean something and make
sure they me meant something well she's
the only one to actually do that in this
bodyweight category in either the snatch
the cleaning jerk oh yeah or the total
right outstanding performance commanding
performance here's the thing she doesn't
have the lengthiest international
pedigree because as a member of Team
North Korea we don't see her competing
that often frankly we don't see North
Korea competing that often especially
around the pandemic and some doping
positives that they dealt with as a team
so every weightlifter from North Korea
basically right now is mysterious we
don't know what kind of team they're
going to show up with and we don't know
what kind of results we're going to see
however so far they've competed twice in
the last call it like four months at the
international level the results have
been Stellar yeah they've been showing
up and kicking butt on the platform
David I know we talked about this last
time we covered them when they competed
but going into the Paris Olympic games
where North Korea is not going to repres
be represented in weightlifting do we
have to cover weightlifting when like
right now it is still expected that
China in the weight categories that are
competing at the Olympics that they are
still going to be the team to beat that
doesn't look like it's going to change
they're going to top Podium but do we
have to cover everything through the
lens of but North Korea isn't there and
who knows what it would have been if
they were are we at that point that's a
great question Phil I think I'm gonna
say no personally that's not to take
anything away from these lifters these
lifters are
phenomenal first off the 45 kilo class
is not a an Olympic body weight category
this is not this is not one of the
women's weight classes in Paris right so
like we get to take her off the table in
order to compete in Paris even if North
K Korea were qualified she'd have to
move up to 49s much more competitive
body weight category right maybe she
could do great there right we see her
compete as a 49 on the international
stage I'll get to that in a second but
the thing is like North Korea has to in
order to qualify for Paris like the team
has to show up they have to compete with
a certain frequency they have to get
they have to earn qualification that
also includes things like and I hate to
say it uh doping testing at a certain
frequency right and we've seen North
Korea struggle with that in the past so
it's a different game it's a longer game
can you consistently show up perform win
medals a acrw points and placings toward
qualification and also pass doping tests
like those are all important measures
here so for me I'm gonna say on this one
no yeah yeah yeah I I think like right
now North Korea has like a lot of this
momentum a lot of hype because as
they're starting to come out compete
they're doing exceptionally well but
yeah we're not going to see them on the
world stage but this I I I hope that we
get to see them in 2028 or at least on
the world stage after the Olympic Games
more frequently because they are setting
World standards and I would love to
actually see them at the same frequency
as the top teams so we can we can
confidently compare them on the platform
as we do our coverage I do want to take
talk real briefly about uh Juan H and
Sims International placings because
we've only seen three of them throughout
her career uh again when we talk about
mysterious weight lifters out of North
Korea it's because we don't know much
more about them beyond what we see on
the international platform uh she's only
Sim's only had three iwf recognized
competition appearances the 2019 Asian
youth Championship she did compete as a
49 kilo lifter and she won the 2023 iwf
Grand Prix number two she competed in
the 45 kilos and one prior to this the
2024 Asian championships where she got
first now a quick reminder China was not
at this year's Asian championships they
pulled out North Korea had a Field Day
racking up medals uh and she gets her
second International gold of 2024 right
but we won't see her get a third in
Paris at least so interesting
interesting setting in the world of
weightlifting you know what where do we
put North Korea in the context of all
this but I think you asked great
questions Phil I just want to point out
here that when it comes to like how
we're talking about North Korea and
talking about them not being in Paris
and what implications that has those are
just my personal opinions when Phil
asked me I just want to be clear folks
those are my personal opinions
Phil what is your favorite thing to what
is your favorite muscle group to train
my last question for you today I have
I'm a sucker for any kind of row I don't
know why I'm always I always have an
affinity for training back uh I get that
like you can train back more often uh or
at least I am able to train back more
often just because there are more
muscles in your back but I love back
training uh more than anything else I
really don't like leg training although
I always feel great afterwards don't
like legs but I will still train them
but I love training back Phil Blackman
bringing the real hard truce Phil thanks
so much for this I always have a great
day this is really the highlight of my
week it's always downhill from here we
record these early in the week for
baron.com I'm David Thomas to joined by
Phil bman thanks for tuning in
[Music]
folks